You have ideas. Good ones. But somewhere between your phone, your laptop, your inbox, and that spreadsheet nobody updates... they die. Not because they're bad. Because your environment kills them.
SpeakUp is a workflow pattern that fixes this. Ideation happens anywhere—your phone, a conversation, a whiteboard. Execution happens in one place—an IDE with AI assistance. Everything gets captured automatically to a system of record. No manual logging. No lost context. No excuses.
In 8 hours, one person produced 30 commits: a working protocol implementation, security verification, this briefing deck, and full documentation. Not a team. One person. The constraint isn't capability. It's environment.
Everything is open source. The briefing, the code, the verification evidence. Link in the description. Go see for yourself.
Let's break down what's actually killing your productivity.
>
The SpeakUp workflow has two active phases and one passive phase.
Now, if you work in government or defense, you're already thinking about objections.
>
Here's the core point: with the right environment, one person can do the work of an entire team.
Here's what to do next:
>
Let me show you what this looks like in practice.
Let's talk about verification. Because in regulated environments, 'trust me' doesn't cut it.
>
If your organization uses Scrum or Agile, you might wonder how this fits.
Let's get practical. How do you actually implement this?
>
Let me address objections I've heard:
Here's the summary:
>